here so last week i don't know what the
exact topic was last week
software no i don't remember but it was
a good conversation that we had and then
near the end of it
this idea of the individual and the
group and how much
i remember reading your article last
week long and it sparked this topic
but then i didn't have time to i was
gonna reread it
that one and then read your new one this
week and i did not
so we'll just see what happens with this
conversation as opposed to trying to
pick off from last one unless you can
one which
would be totally welcome yeah i
um what i remember was
or is it was about the person
and the relation to the group the group
seen as a possible community so
what is the relation between you and
another person
like another member and what is your
relation between you
and the entity of the community
yeah because there was something about i
think if your
article from last week there was
something about like you never actually
do something for the community you do it
for other individuals
which is true because even if you're
doing it for the community it's for the
individuals in the community
but there's a certain level of the
community i'm part of that like i said
with a composting guy right like
yes he's doing it for but he's not doing
it for me and he's not doing it for like
the individual we all benefit from it
but it's not like it is being done for
the community same with like when i
sleep the yoga room floor like it's not
it's for the community and so like i get
it
and yet it's just like a little bit
sometimes it is for that and so i was
looking to flush out that a little bit
more
oh adam's here
we don't need to be silent while he's
coming
welcome adam discussing the
the topic of um individual verses not
verses versus like kind of what it is
that way
the individual versus the group like
that
relationship are we
is my relationship with every single
individual is there a
relationship to the community itself
because the communities also like if one
person leaves the community
is it a whole new community or is it
like my body right skin cells slough off
and i'm a new whole new person every
seven years but not really
okay watch me
i am i expected to respond to that right
now i don't know we're just having an
open conversation
yeah i feel like i want to hear more um
from
you know the conversation that happened
before
uh this one so i can kind of understand
what and riff off of what was
you know really where this topic came
from
maybe i can make a little introduction
if
you really agree so we were talking last
time about this
relations between people and the
relation between
a person and an entity and
i used in writing
my article about this i use
this this option
to think about something when i writing
about something
i don't know if anybody of you know
hannah ahren
she is a famous person in germany
she was in i think boston
a professor in a university after the
second world war or in the second world
war
and she experienced the same
so uh to put it in in a few sentences
from my perspective we as as
humans have um this stability
and this necessity to
invent entities which are higher
than we we
see ourselves this entity can
be named like religion company
moral ethics standards communities
whatever you want to see as this
and my first question in in my article
was
can i find some basic simple
biological rules which are already
embedded in our life experience from the
beginning
and i see this when i look to
a boy or girl from four years
playing when you see such a little kid
playing it plays
in different roles it is a nurse it is a
doctor it is a fireworker
it switched from one second to another
second to be the policeman
or to be just a little kid
[Music]
in in a scene so this person is able to
switch
and when you talk with psychologists
about this
phenomena you um you get the response
that you are populated by a lot of
personalities when you are
little and
your way to socialize to find your
your setting in a society and your
your personal point which
enables you to develop relations to
others
this is exactly the moment when you
develop your
ego and this is the moment when one of
these
personalities um
occurs at like the winner of of your
body
so you are populated by a lot of
personalities and
finally one of these personalities is
the winner
so um but this personality
you can call it also it's a kind of
software
and you
you add
ideas to this entity
so it is a very short step
to to develop
other ideas of entities which are
separated from the body of one person
and a company or a community
or a group a team
is nothing else than this so our
[Music]
in our last conversation i pointed
to to this issue that whatever i do
for earth community
is finally something i do for one
specific person or for two people or for
um for for a team who is working on
something when i donate some hours to
work in the garden or things like this
so um
[Music]
i'm i'm interested in in your view on
this
and and this was the idea also to find
this topic for this talk
yeah it's a it's a really interesting
topic
i i definitely have to just say i not
any kind of expert on this i like the
example of
sweeping the sweeping the yoga room
floor um you know you know this is going
to benefit
the next people that come you don't even
know if that's going to be a group
or just one person um you don't even
have an
individual in mind you have a
hey the next people that are going to
use this space
uh one one of the things that comes to
mind is a self-care
type of thing that has this it's just
it's so connected so for me it
i can think of exercise so exercise
is really important for me um it keeps
me
happy and mentally healthy and it's kind
of selfish
like um i'm doing this for me
and that's how i have to think
um but the result is that i'm better for
other people
if i don't exercise for two or three
weeks like
it doesn't you know i'm not as good uh
i'm not the best version of myself and
that comes off in how i treat other
people but when i'm exercising regularly
i'm actually treating other people
better because i'm taking care of me
so it's so weird how this is connected
that's i mean that's what comes to mind
that it's connected
um i i can jump in there if uh i
have i i think it's it's not only
connected like these two
phenomenon of interpersonal connection
and what you might call like a the
social
the culture that emerges out of all of
those
interpersonal connections
they're connected and i think that they
both they go both ways
and if i seem distracted just now it was
it was i was doing my best to listen
while i found a podcast from
jim rutt uh with uh
jessica flack on complex system dynamics
it's episode 48 of the jim rutt show
and i just this this whole question was
calling back to mind this
this episode which i loved and they talk
about this thing called coarse graining
which is a uh where
com complex systems can be broken down
into simpler sub components
and uh and the
the those they talk about how it's
in in biology and and forgive me i'm not
a scientist i can't recall exactly how
they described it but from what i
understood from that episode they talked
about how
there is this there's a set of signals
that are being sent
up if you want to call it that like up
to the to
the level of of in biology the level of
the organism
um uh and then also back
down to the level of the cell and i
would
i my intuition is that the same thing
would work culturally where you've got
all of these
these connections happening on the micro
interpersonal level sending a signal up
to the culture but then in the same way
the culture is
reflecting a signal back down to the
cell perhaps reinforcing priors
prior belief systems
interesting because danielle you had
said that you see
exercise as somewhat selfish
and when i went for my walk this morning
i um had the exact opposite
thought about it like i was like
yesterday someone had asked in the game
b
space what what the metric is right are
we closer to game b
and i was it just pop i was like oh well
how many decisions do you make in a day
that are omni-win
and of course we can all make omni win
decisions all day but what is
um the more decisions we can make the
more we can be aware where we can't make
optimum decisions or don't want to make
them
the more we can work towards creating
game b right the closer we get to there
but when i went for my walk this morning
i was like this is omni win like i'm
like
i'm going for a walk in nature nature's
getting something out of it but that's
just my weird belief system
i'm getting something out of it and the
world is getting something because i'm a
better person
my kid gets a better parent you know
like there's and
it isn't rivalrous everyone can
experience this maybe not at the same
moment that was the other thing i was
like and i'm going early in the day
because it's busy later so there's less
people later and with covet 19 that
matters a little more
and i don't remember my point of that
was
but there was and then when juan was
talking about the um
the thought of little kids with their
they have multiple
multiple personalities and then one
sticks that's not how i view
childhood and yet when you were talking
that's very similar to the subtle knife
the golden compass and they have their
demons
and i'm wondering if they got that from
child psychology or
if it's that they have little animals in
this
in this story that that change until
they get to be
until they they um solidify in one shape
and then that becomes their demon for
the rest of their lives so like the
people who live on the sea have a
dolphin or a seagull and other people
have you know
meerkats and other things and um
that is although that's just children's
story like having a society
of those different personalities like
there's something about the community
like the people who live on the sea
who they need to have seagulls right
whereas someone who has more
of a diverse community needs to have
different kinds so that they can have
something else to contribute right maybe
yours is a mouse and go into something
tiny and mine's a tiger and can you know
like
be more more powerful if there's
the individual like i like i'm i am a
scientist
and the cells and the the individual
that message down like that is how we
have to create game b we have to figure
out how to do it without the hierarchy
because
cell doesn't there's hierarchy but
there's not hierarchy at the same time
my cells aren't arguing with the being
with me right there if they are it's
cancer like there's a problem
and at the same time i don't have a um
i don't remember sorry i lost my train
of father well this this reminds me of
going to this idea of um
wit not taking more than you need so
you have a community you have a group of
people
and any one of them could
be taking so much more
than they need as a person it's easy to
do
and i think the analogy with the with
the cells and the body
is like yeah you have this symbiotic
relationship and you have like the liver
and the heart
and they're all they're they're both
their own thing uh
but if the liver just is like i'm gonna
take all the resources
then not only does it kill the heart but
it kills itself and like so you have all
these
these different things and uh yeah not
taking more than you need
might be part of that dynamic of
individual uh in a community
um that could be you know something to
watch out for
it could be harmful could be you know if
you have these spiritual practices
or whatever you're doing your awareness
practices
to help yourself understand
where you are on that continuum
comes to mind
adam had just asked in that in the
comment section what i meant by
hierarchy and
i meant authority like someone else
outside dictating
what i do or don't do is to me what i
don't want
in hierarchy yet delegating a
coordinator delegating this
is to me somewhat not hierarchy but it's
it's a
very gray area and this is also part of
what i was
um i had this argument strong word but
about the masks versus no masks for
kobit 19
and i had this epiphany of like i'm
actually more okay
being having a virus have authority over
me because i can't um
argue it right it just is what it is
it's
i can't argue it i can't i can't um
make it be anything different than it is
whereas my government
or other people controlling me is a
completely different
like it feels different because we could
get them to do something different
they're not doing it right right like
there's something
different about that whereas the virus
has no authority no anything it just is
what it is
and yet it's control it's changing our
entire society which is very different
to me than like
what is then the response to that okay
if i can respond to that uh i
my intuition on just that that point and
this question
in general of authority uh is that
ideally we would be able to construct a
system
that is so obviously good that
it immediately benefits the people
the players in that system such that
you would have to really have some
severe mental illness to not want to
participate in the system
and you'd um
you would never really need to be forced
into it
and and then another ideal and this is
my cats coming to say hello
another ideal i think would be to have
have the how the system really be
um impregnable like
against bad actors sure
we all have to account for the fact that
there will be sociopaths there will be
people who
try to do the most harm out of just for
whatever reason
and the system itself should be able to
flag
something like that and and deal with it
rather quickly
in the same way going back to the cell
example that we have
i don't know if it's every day or every
week or every month but we always have
cancerous cells coming up
but the body just naturally has a way to
take care of it
so in terms of authority i don't like in
in terms of like autocracy i i'd agree
that like
having that sort of authority gets toxic
but like a um
if there's sort of a mutually agreed
upon submission
to this to this this way of being
that that we we've all agreed upon is is
beneficial to society
like you could take buddhism obviously
not all examples of buddhism but
but some examples of buddhism uh can
look like that
it could be an authority but a lot of
people in buddhist societies just agree
like this this works
there's also this cancer comes up a lot
right that like that's
the cells get out in my um group on
wednesdays
one of the things that comes up that
kylie talks about is um
that the cells in your body the whatever
hierarchy authority
we feed the cells and they do their job
we don't require them to first do their
job and then get fed
right like it's like well we're not
going to give you any nutrients unless
you're pumping the heart like it's like
no
you can't have that unless and there's
very much
like that also feels like the authority
right where it's like unless you're
gonna comply
you don't get the things and there's
like the group if i'm part of the group
if i'm truly part of the group
i'm good with us coming up with rules
and the our
collectively decided on um rules or
whatever we want to call them
we've agreed to we've had a say in it
you can either leave or not it has to be
voluntary also
then i'm okay with with following that
authority that hierarchy
because it's the like it's not one
person who's decided they know better
than
everyone else in my individual self on
my individual self
it's something bigger than that and i
don't know
quite what it is that i'm like yes if
there's 50 of us deciding on something
even if i don't agree with the rule i'm
more likely to abide by it
than the government who we voted in
coming up with it
even if it was 50 people then we voted
someone and then they decided
oh i know what it is it's democracy
voice versus
feeling like no
well i'll tell you what my experience is
that you've got community
it's made up of human beings and human
beings
are messy and they bring experiences
good bad and otherwise and
nobody's perfect and i guess one thing
that comes to mind to watch out for is
codependency and i've experienced
uh i've met some folks who have
codependent behavior
and you know it it's really tricky
because
there's funny stuff that happens where
uh on this and i'm still interested in
this individual versus
group tension not they're against each
other but
there can be tension and it's like oh to
a codependent person
if you say you know no i'm not going to
participate in that event
or i'm going to do something else you
know
this time that's good for me um the
codependent person
can be unsure how to interpret that
that can be confusing or seen as a
threat or seen as like
wait a second are you saying i'm you
know we're not good enough
um there's all sorts of funny thing that
funny things that can happen
when an individual um is like
oh no i'm not gonna come to the dinner
party but i'll show up after
um and like a healthy person might be
like okay cool
we'll see you then and then some folks
might not understand what's going on
there
uh that just comes to mind
um codependency can be tricky
in in groups
yeah um
the the umbrella overall this
video podcasts this community
and how to build a community how to
start
what are basic rules or important tools
or
important ideas to think about on the
way
to start something so
in relation to this codependence
or to what was said before
um my argumentation goes in the
direction
if you imagine if you simulate
such an entity which is above
maybe you run into trouble with
authority
or dictatorship or whatever or maybe
it's it's very balanced and you
personally feel comfortable with this
for any of these entities you need a
kind of speaker
and
in another discussion about black lives
matters
it was an interesting aspect
to discover how the
the law sees
a company or an entity like an
association
and if you if you are not so much
comfortable
with seeing a community as a company
maybe you can imagine a little bit more
because even many communities are
founding an association to cover the
the property issue um that it's
something like an
association and if you see an
association you have a speaker
and if you have a speaker and the
speaker is member
and speaker you have
you in you implement automatically a
hierarchy
and that's what that was my point in
this
interesting because what um a few months
ago in january february i got made a mod
of the game d space and the difference
between
pre being a mod and speaking up and
moderating moderating people who were
who were like peers felt different
then now every time i i'm like i feel
like like i want to take off the
moderator hat and be like this is
jubilee not
like not the advanced moderator because
and then it's like people are like like
putting things on the hierarchy
authority and being like you guys need
to solve this and this and that and it's
like
i feel very much like i'm in a parental
role and i hate it like it's like
no that's just not what we're doing
we're not replaying game a
like figure your shit out like just you
figure it out like you
or other people step in because it's
like people don't feel
the i kind of think what the word is
the the authority isn't the only word
that's coming to mind to be unless
they've been given the role of moderate
men
to step in and be like hey this like
because if we're all mods and admins
then anyone can step in
anyone can see it and there's 2 000 of
us and someone's going to see it much
sooner than the mods who are really
really um but it's like just this like
flagging and like
someone punished them and this it's just
very
it becomes that like the speaker and
then am i speaking for me
or am i speaking for game b or am i
speaking for the mod group and where's
my loyalty and then
like it's just it's important messiness
but it's messiness sure it gets
uh it gets really tricky too when uh
so it sounds like there is this thing
where as you step
up in responsibility um maybe you're not
even the speaker of the group
but you have some responsibility
then people are looking to you as more
of a representative
like i'm just you know regular person
out here in this community or
i'm the treasurer or i'm whatever it
might be
and uh the awareness that
we have to understand human nature if
you say i'm a part of this thing
or especially i have some responsibility
uh in in this thing the thing being the
group
then um if you
do something good or bad
but i'm thinking like if you do
something bad people don't just see it
as
oh you know jubilee messed up
or or is bad they associate it with the
whole
thing so some dirt comes out on
you know p all people make mistakes and
whatever the heck
it could be and then it's like oh game b
is like this and it's like well that's
an individual and like
that's just this human nature um
to to watch out for uh or just be aware
of or
something like that right i'd love to
jump in
there so
for my taste uh i think that the current
model
of moderation in online spaces
is deeply flawed i think that
what we ought to look at
is tribal models of communication
and what i mean by that is is like
sorry someone's running a blender
it's lunch time i hope it's gonna be
delicious
it's not for me but i bet it is um
so so what i mean by that is like a
dunbar size group you've got
150 200 people how do how does
moderation happen
in in those groups we are apes we have a
an intuited sense of authority an
intuitive sense of skills
an intuitive sense of reputation uh
and we can do that for about 150 to 200
people before
we just can't keep track of all of that
minutia
all that data that allows us to make
this again the small decisions that
create
the broader culture so when you put a
bunch of monkeys
on the internet we're trying to apply
these old models
and we're filling in all the blanks
based on like people's
profile picture or lack of profile
picture or punctuation or lack of
punctuation
we're we're trying to fill in all of
that
data and and making a lot of assumptions
about the people we're talking to uh add
to that
the fact that so many of the people
like i'm noticing in in like the portal
uh podcast facebook group is terrible
so terrible i don't know if you're if
you've uh
spent any time there but it's like half
of the people there are just total
trolls
and the worst part is is that the the
people that i see
as being like oh you're a smart person
why are you even engaging with this
um so at uh um i forget
uh who was making daniel was making this
point that that reflects poorly on
the podcast which then reflects poorly
on
whatever idw you want to call it um
so to backtrack all of that i think we
we
need to build from the ground up
a system that has the benefits of a dump
our sized community like what are the
things we
really care about when in communication
with people we care that they're in good
faith
we care that they know what the hell
they're talking about and we care
that they are listening and responding
thoughtfully to uh
to me like or you or to to others
and and uh we care that they
that they're not power hungry that
they're not just trying to manipulate
the system to put themselves at the top
like these are all things that we care
about in a in a
smaller dunbar size physical irl
community
and it's not impossible to create that
digitally
uh yeah i'll look into that co
sicko so i can't pronounce that
juan just posted something in the text
um but the thing i wanted to say about
moderation
is in a in a dunbar sized community
people just allow
others to make decisions based on their
merit in that field and i know
meritocracy is a very
like sensitive subject but you you let
the hunter decide where to go to hunt
you don't say well everyone gets a
everyone gets
a an opinion we all get to you know
take turns deciding where to go hunt and
you let the
the woman the doula decide where
and how this baby is getting born that's
not a democratized decision like these
these models of meritocracy are built in
and
intuited but that up until i think
probably the last
decade was like impossible to do
digitally
we didn't have the skills we didn't have
the interconnectivity and most
importantly we didn't have the global
democratic access to the web but now
and certainly in the next decade or two
everyone will have
a smartphone every human will have
access to the internet
you know borrowing some kind of
catastrophic event
so in that in that new
economy it seems to me like getting
really drilling
down on what are people's strengths who
has good ideas
and how do we how do we put those
uh people with those strengths in
positions of
power so that they can manipulate the
correct resources
to bring those ideas to fruition to
benefit the whole
and then into just in such a system
there would be a
co-moderation you wouldn't have people
people's uh ability to
to manipulate a field of study or to
manipulate a community would be
dependent on their
hyper-quantified like input into that
community
someone wouldn't just be well like a
king wouldn't be able to just be born a
king
and never really earned that power but
they'd actually have to earn it
and and and maintain
a qualitative like input to maintain
that power
so this reminds me of the sort of
business card non-business card thing
that has been talked about sometime
where
like hey i have these skills i'm
available for these things here's some
things you might want to know about me
and we wanted i mean i thought there
would be an awesome way to have like a
reputation system
so other people can verify
i mean linkedin has some stuff like this
but linkedin is linkedin it's like
for careers and jobs there might be some
skills
that i'm gonna well i know there are
some skills i'm not gonna put on my
linkedin
that's like for employers that's like
game a
that's like maybe that'll disappear one
day
but what you're saying part of what
you're saying reminds me of that
uh a reputation card of
of skills um and you're saying this is
much more natural in the dunbar
space and i i could also attest to that
smaller groups communities spend time in
um burning man communities and that's
what it's like it's like oh everybody
knows so and so is great at that thing
like you don't even question that they
have all the expertise
it's very frustrating when it goes the
other way i did a bunch of event
planning
and then i joined a new group that was
doing some event planning
i tried to tell them hey i've been doing
event planning for like six years
there were some people who were kind of
at the core of it
that really was close to their heart and
they had some ideas
and i was like hey i don't want to step
on your toes but
i've seen this happen before it'd be
much better if we did
slightly modified what you're talking
about telling you
it'll work better and they just didn't
want to hear it and
like my six years of doing some event
planning meant nothing to them and it's
like
so i actually had to step away i'm like
well these folks don't
want to listen at all and we have to
also on the flip side be quick to say
i actually don't know much about this
topic and
that that needs to be natural as well
i think there was this concept that i
was playing with last week and i brought
it up in my
omega group was that there's
this binary of people are generally
either overestimators or underestimators
on their own skill level
so i look at life as like a normal curve
for every single trait and you're
i'm someone who if i'm not the smartest
person in the room or i can see people
who are smarter than me and so i don't
think i'm smart right like i see people
who are better than me and so i don't
think i'm as good
and so therefore i'm bad there's people
who are the exact opposite who we're
like
well i can see there's few people who
are worse than me so i'm awesome
and that like being an underestimator
has made me who i am i show up
differently
people in a meritocracy they're going to
trust me less and yet i have more to
give because i'm an underestimator
right like if i think i can't make a
meal for you and if i and you're like a
chef
i'm going to make a five course dinner
right because i'm an underestimator i'm
underestimating my skills
if i think i'm the best chef i'm going
to make a kfc or sorry uh
macaroni and cheese like it's like
there's this
your reputation but also like your
how you present yourself to the world
but it's not true
right like my actual skill level is
higher
than average on most things but because
i'm not the smart
not the highest i think i'm the lowest
right like that's kind of where i put
myself and being aware of that
helps me move myself up a little bit but
how do we account for that how do we
allow for
people like trump who are like i'm the
best at everything when they clearly
aren't versus the people who are like i
don't know i'm not very good at that
but clearly are and that's
i don't know how we do that especially
in a in a dunbar
or in any any size group
that's such a huge question and i i
don't know if you guys know
alfred adler is he writes a lot about
he's a
like a was a contemporary of freud and
wrote
a lot about uh superiority inferiority
complexes and
i my personal opinion is that we have to
we have to first of all get
get develop a community
that is immune to the dunning-kruger
effect
uh to people who think that they know
more than they know
uh because that's not an option that you
mentioned um
but i think it's the most toxic version
of one's relationship to one's true
intelligence that combined with
narcissism and power you get
you get trump uh and
so to first do that you have to ask
what does it mean to know well there's
objective truths like gravity
but even even if gravity
and surely there are undiscovered
there's i'm sure there's
whole fields of undiscovered objective
truths that we don't know
because we don't know them they're not
an objective truth and similarly you can
have
an entire group of people that because
they're
all surrounded by others who believe
uh something it it effectively becomes
objective truth
within their world like there's entire
people who think that
bill gates is trying to inject little
computers to
control their brain uh with you know a
cova vaccine like this this is this is a
real thing it's
really sad like i see people who who are
uh i would say like dunning-kruger
adjacent like they
they do all the research and they they
really they're gonna get down to the
bottom of things but the whole time they
don't realize that they've never stepped
out of
their realm so to
the first step to me is to inoculate a
sense of vulnerability or
yeah condition people to
to say what they think is true open
themselves up to
honest and constructive criticism to
those truths
so that an objective truth for that
community may emerge
and one of the good things that i've
experienced
that might help people
be allowed to say when they're not good
at something is
uh opportunities for teaching
so in some art communities
and yeah mostly art communities there's
lots of people that say
hey i have the skill by the way and
they'll even do this on our online
groups
anyone who wants to learn how to do
whatever paint
weld spin fire uh
they're very clear that come hang out
with me i'll teach you how to do
whatever
and so that um being clear
that i'll teach you uh lets people say
okay yeah i'll come to the class or i
don't know this certain thing
um whereas like if you're if you don't
have people explicitly saying i'll teach
you this skill
then you might not want to admit that
you don't know the skill
or you you might think i'll just go
learn this on my own until i figure it
out because i'm too afraid
to say that i don't know it i don't know
that's just something that i've noticed
um kind of works is people explicitly
saying i'll
you know i'll teach you um
and have a class or just call me and
come hang out i'm probably already doing
the thing and
that's uh that's that might be a helpful
um part of this
i did a um a video yesterday and i'm
having this thought that i'm
monopolizing this conversation but um i
did videos today
based on rebel wisdoms um the god
cancel god and what came out of that for
me was like okay so there's cancel
culture which is clearly toxic but what
would creation culture look like and
it's literally the flip side it's like
you have to be perfect in cancer culture
it doesn't matter how woke you are if
you say one thing that's not you're done
and the opposite of that right that we
like allow people to get it wrong
and have roads to redemption and allow
for that that learning process like
we're so
like your kid has to know what they're
good at and be like a genius at it by
four they're behind it's like well
they're never gonna be an olympic
gymnast right they were probably never
going to be an olympic gymnast
but 80 year olds could take up maybe not
eight-year-olds in gymnastics but they
take up basketball or something right
like there's no
creating a culture of like what does
creation culture look like was the
question and then i answered it but
hey that's awesome and going back to the
thing where hey
people nerf themselves they shortchange
themselves on
their skills you had like the cooking
example or whatever
um all i would say for that
is encouragement and affirmation have a
culture that
out of nowhere um you know without
asking
makes it a point to encourage and affirm
people and say hey by the way i just
want to know let you know you know
you're an amazing chef
um you know we don't get enough
encouragement and affirmation
i mean freud was mentioned most of what
i know goes
and this stuff is connected to why do
people have to act
like they are like there's the
nerfing people that don't do what they
could and you said there's examples
where people
like try to act like they can do things
that they can't
and most of that i observe comes from
not getting enough unconditional love
as a child and then you're always making
up for it you can never show cracks in
your armor
kind of thing um that's a harder
uh nut to crack is the big ego side
but for people who are not living in
their potentials you know them your
their your friend
encourage them and tell them hey by the
way you're great at this thing like
and you know the more you do that maybe
you know it gets into
their uh their self part because how do
you know someone's not living up to
their potential
like if it's an individual like it's not
necessarily i'm the best
i know if you're telling me i'm the best
chef you're lying to me like i'm not my
kid won't eat my food like i know
and truthfully i don't want to be told
on the best shelf i want to be told it's
okay i suck at it
you know what i mean like it doesn't my
worth is a human being is not determined
by my ability to do that and yet i can
sous chef
right like i can cut up the carrots i
can do that tell me what to do i can do
that no problem
i can follow a recipe and so like what i
want is the
the allowance to suck at it that is what
i'm creating in society like instead of
needing to put on this armor saying like
listen here are my cracks accept me or
don't
and the more we're willing to do that
it's hard but the more we're willing to
that more we give everyone else
permission too and that's the community
i want to be part of is the one that
does allow that
yeah that's good
we have sometimes workshops
with students from universities and
one of the best compliments i get was
[Music]
thank you for the opportunity to fail
failing doesn't appear in the education
in my university so
i'm not so much in
thinking about finding the truth i
i am more in favor with people like
carl popper um who
mentioned that we fail
and it's just a question to fail better
so um um
in this case um
i see only a simulation of anything
like an entity like community
company or whatever if you look to the
more or less physical facts it's a paper
it's a sheet
it's a contract it's maybe a building
which is
used for a company or whatever but
what happened really what i experienced
really is my thoughts about the other
members
and and if i clean a room because
i want to donate a clean room
to the next group for the next yoga
class
finally i want to donate a kind of
peace and happiness to myself in doing
this
and um so from this point
i think coming back to this idea what is
a community or or how to create a
community
i agree with you believe it's um it's a
question of
feeling having this feeling
of having space for developing
develop myself this is what
i want when i look to communicate
to communities
i don't know if we stayed on topic for
this hour but i'm loving this
conversation
and that's always the beauty of these
it's like they start one place and go
another
i would like to suggest for next week
and i'm open to any other suggestions
but there's this concept that adriel my
brother also together
he's in the gaming projects together
tech um is this idea of trying to fail
like actually giving yourself perm like
to
what would be the crappiest project we
could create right and so
i would like to discuss what would it
take to truly try to fail at community
right like one of the worst things we
could do and not just
just to because it's kind of fun right
not not do them let's not start with
failing communities
because that's also piece of it for game
a for me anyway is that we have
businesses communities anything that
starts nine out of ten of them fail
and then we only look at the successful
ones and we're like we give them like 9
out of 10 tech companies 910 restaurants
and 910
and it's like so they did something
right no they won
the lottery like that's not the same
thing as looking at
how do we help the other nine succeed or
help them give their their best thing
and so
trying to fail and then failing at
failing is
is a beautiful way to get to success
but i'm open to other other suggestions
that's pretty cool i think that's
awesome
that's uh that's very smart
do you think there's any relationship
between people's
resistance to uh
like like being abnormal
or outside of the box or just behaving
or thinking or saying things that are
contrary to their
communities belief systems i
i have a strong sense that there's a
relationship between
that phenomenon and people's reluctance
to fail
like it all comes back to this
this feeling of of
well which could be a very deep
emotional fear for primates and
maybe mammals in general which is being
ostracized from the group
if you if you go out on a limb and
propose something that has
runs contrary to what the group is is
uh thinking or feeling
sure that that's a bet that could earn
you a lot of
points in the group could earn you a lot
of reputation if it works out and if
people agree
but it's a bet that if people don't
agree
they could kill you and
similarly trying something new is
in my mind like along a similar spectrum
you've you're
you can you can try this thing very
publicly
and be seen
as a failure for having not
achieved that thing but and this is sort
of
weaving its way towards an answer to
this question which is
how do you inoculate a community that
celebrates attempts
celebrates heterodoxy that celebrates
outside of the box thinking and doesn't
immediately label that
as as racist or whatever prejudice
and i think we're doing that
there's a concept in my community that
um within the community is it safe
enough to try
right so you put out something and it's
like it doesn't need to get 100
consensus is this safe enough to try for
a while so you can get some feedback and
see
and creation culture i think having a
culture of
um whatever you say we're gonna figure
it out we're gonna deal with it right
we're not gonna cancel you unless it's
so egregious
and then we're going to own that yes
that means death even
right like ostracizing you from the
group
is a form of that
yeah and i think it depends on what it
is i think adam what you're saying about
like
uh tricky conversations uh
outside of the box ideas uh that's
tough um i you know i noticed the whole
cultural threat of yeah if you um
you know if you don't toe the line of a
certain maybe like a social justice
thing or something and you're like well
wait a second
i'm not sure that's accurate you know
that could be very bad
a good examples of this i've seen
mostly from my experience in burning man
culture
what they do is they say what we care
about
most is participation
we don't care about like success we
just care about participation and
there's flow arts communities
that love it when new people show up and
you don't have to
you this could be your first time doing
it it's just cool that you're there
and i think the word is participation
and that's it it's not success or it has
to be awesome or there's always going to
be somebody who's
been doing it longer than you um i think
participation helps me
think about a word that describes
it's not quite like may i don't know if
it's a celebration of failure i
i want to explore that idea more um but
it's a celebration of hey you're
you're here and you're trying that's
what we care about
well i call it anti-fragility
you've you grow from these failures you
you you and we are anti-fragile as
humans you can
if you bend and you don't break then
you're stronger as a result of it
and the the
the other thing you mentioned about like
the flow arts community celebrating
people's
just uh what i would call like good
faith
participation i'd say this would be
another tenet of
of a community that we build where it's
not an option to participate
you must participate you can't just
be a recluse and expect to
expect to extract the
the benefits of this community
however you your participation doesn't
need to be of a certain quality it just
needs to be done in good faith
and the beauty of that is it's a
perfectly democratic
request anyone can participate
in some way in good faith
i do um when i hear a lot of those
things about participation as somebody
with a um
energy disability i'm always like oh god
then the participation's gonna be set at
like 15 hours a week or 20 hours a week
whatever it is for some people it's
gonna be really low
it's like oh i have all this time to
golf and for me it's gonna feel like
five full-time jobs
and so that there's and i don't think
that's what you were saying adam i think
the quality underneath was the
participation is part
is in that that like my participation
might be five hours a week
even if um other people can do more that
i'm looking for where i'm participating
where i can where i can have the biggest
impact for my five hours if that's what
i can give
yeah exactly it's just that each uh
from each according or yeah from each
according to their abilities to reach
according to their needs
building building a community that
really
has a subjective like
per person expectation and and
based on time because maybe if you're
the most energetic person
and you've you've signed up for this
heroic task but
you wake up that day and you're just
feeling really crappy you should not
have to do that thing
it's all compassion this is just this is
an ethic of compassion we're coming up
on the hour i want to give everyone a
quick chance to have a closing thought i
also wanted to mention i have the
solution rising on wednesday it's in the
same zoom room
and it's on shelter which is very
pertinent to community
so for the first time we're going to be
discussing like literally shelter not
community we've had ones on community
before
but i'm sure community will come into it
but what could ten thousand people and a
hundred thousand dollars do
to help people be sheltered i don't know
that's why we haven't tackled this one
yet but we're tackling it this week
and um is everyone okay next week with
having the topic be failure how can we
fail at this
yeah okay and everyone like to give
their closing comments if they have any
and then i will stop the recording and
go hang out with my kid uh sure i'll
just go off of the last thing we said
um i back off a bit
from uh participation
as a requirement and i think that
participation could look
different to different people in flow
arts communities
yeah there are some folks you know maybe
with certain disabilities
uh that maybe what they can do is like
you know provide drinks or something i i
just don't know i
i'm pro-inclusion and so it's like well
if someone
can't do that but these are their
friends you know in other spaces
is there something else they can do if
they can't do the flow art thing
uh i i like that
the whole conversation's been good
um i just i'm grateful to have a seat at
this table
and i look forward to talking with you
all again
thank you
yeah um nice um
even nice to meet new new faces
sometimes and
i think failing or or this
feeling that failing is not something
negative
that it's an opportunity for innovation
is very important so
[Music]
i think every community or
whatever project is highly recommended
to open spaces to fail because
only in these spaces they will meet any
kind of
future sustainability or things like
this
so let's meet sixty
thank you everyone uh thank you for
joining us adam it was nice meeting you
and thank you juan and daniel for
showing up as usual